John McDonald Papers MS164
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
John McDonald Papers
1970 -- 2017
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
McDonald, John
MS164
28.55 Linear Feet
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of John McDonald, 2010-2017.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in two series: Unprocessed accessions and 2017 accessions.
Biographical / Historical
John McDonald is a Professor of Music at Tufts University. He received the 2009 Lillian and Joseph Leibner Award for Distinguished Teaching and Advising from Tufts University, and was named the 2007 MTNA-Shepherd Distinguished Composer of the Year by the Music Teachers National Association. McDonald served as chair of the Music Department, Tufts University, from 2000 to 2003.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains John McDonald's musical manuscripts and scores, audiocassette recordings of his performances, project files, correspondence, and concert programs and reviews.
McDonald, John; Faculty papers
- Additional accessions, 1975 -- 2007; MS164.001; 4.8 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  This series is not arranged.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Musical scores, 1997 -- 2007; MS164-001 (Box data_value_missing_b789cd75bae62d9a9388b818aac858b5, Box 1)
  - Performance recordings (1 of 3), 1975 -- 2005; MS164-002 (Box data_value_missing_e80aca4a093b91ed8defab42ef17bc87, Box 2)
    Scope and Contents
    Audio recordings of John McDonald's performances, circa 1975-2005, on cassette.
  - Performance recordings (2 of 3), 1975 -- 2005; MS164-003 (Box data_value_missing_ec35ab584a4393e97582e9e199f17669, Box 3)
  - Performance recordings (3 of 3), 1975 -- 2005; MS164-004 (Box data_value_missing_56a3bdb5ad4f8666ad485a4fd255fba0, Box 4)
- 2017 accessions, circa 1970 -- 2017; MS164.002; 23.75 Linear Feet
  This series is arranged in received order.
  This series is open for research.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transferred by John McDonald, 2017, accession MS-2018-018.
  This series contains manuscripts, sketches, project files, concert programs and reviews, scores, and correspondence produced by or about John McDonald.
  - Manuscripts: Juvenilia and Opus 1-150, circa 1976 -- 1995; MS164.002.005; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 5)
  - Manuscripts: Opus 151-272, circa 1988 -- 1997; MS164.002.006; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 6)
  - Manuscripts: Opus 273-367f, circa 1992 -- 2002; MS164.002.007; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 7)
  - Manuscripts: Opus 368-439, circa 2000 -- 2008; MS164.002.008; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 8)
  - Manuscripts: Opus 440-500, circa 2008 -- 2012; MS164.002.009; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 9)
  - Manuscripts: Opus 501-627, circa 2012 -- 2017; MS164.002.010; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 10)
  - Piano Album Manuscripts 1; Misc. files, circa 1987 -- 2011; MS164.002.011; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 11)
  - Piano Album Manuscripts 2; Misc. files; Sketch Notebooks, circa 1987 -- 2009; MS164.002.012; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 12)
  - Sketches in envelopes, circa 1986 -- 2002; MS164.002.013; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 13)
  - Sketches in envelopes; bound scores; project files, circa 1979 -- 2016; MS164.002.014; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 14)
  - Concert programs and reviews; projects, circa 1990 -- 2008; MS164.002.015; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 15)
  - Flute music; bassoon music; sketches, scores, copies, project files, circa 1986 -- 2014; MS164.002.016; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 16)
  - Scores, copies, project files, circa 1995 -- 2016; MS164.002.017; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 17)
  - Project files; scores and copies; WRA/SME programs, circa 1986 -- 2015; MS164.002.018; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 18)
  - Reviews, programs, project files, correspondence, scrapbooks, circa 2000 -- 2016; MS164.002.019; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 19)
  - Juvenilia OHIO; reviews, programs, project files, circa 1970 -- 2002; MS164.002.020; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 20)
  - Scores copies and Projects1 (Tufts Office), circa 1980 -- 2015; MS164.002.021; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 21)
  - Scores copies and Projects2 (Tufts Office), circa 1980 -- 2015; MS164.002.022; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 22)
  - Large format scores, circa 1985 -- 1998; MS164.002.023; .4 Linear Feet (Box data_value_missing_36aa73f5779f31005bca97c06b9d3467, Box 23)
  - Large format scores, circa 1983 -- 1996; MS164.002.024; .4 Linear Feet (Box data_value_missing_36aa73f5779f31005bca97c06b9d3467, Box 24)
  - Scores, circa 1982 -- 2009; MS164.002.025; .25 Linear Feet (Box data_value_missing_36aa73f5779f31005bca97c06b9d3467, Box 25)
  - Large format scores, circa 1987 -- 2004; MS164.002.026; 1.1 Linear Feet (Box data_value_missing_36aa73f5779f31005bca97c06b9d3467, Box 26)